That was because my brother and I
因為我跟哥哥
weren't born with any power.
出生時並沒有任何腦力
We were Bell Peppers.
是個甜椒
Alice...
愛麗絲…
What...
什麼…
He traveled back in time
卡連回到過去
to alter Alice's destiny.
打算改變愛麗絲的命運
We can stop Togetsu's mainframe, BABE, from functioning.
讓渡月的控制電腦貝比停止運作
How does that sound?
這個方法如何
The researches on Red Strings
紅色繫線的研究報告
and their plans of operations are all in there.
以及實行計畫 都在貝比裡
Yuito, before we set out for Togetsu, I need to have a word with you.
結人 去渡月之前我有事想跟你說
A word with me?
跟我說
Let's not talk about it here.
在這裡有點難說
We should talk outside.
我們到外面去吧
Since everyone is present, you should listen to it too.
既然各位也在場 也來聽聽吧
What is this about?
你要說什麼
It's your father.
你的父親
It's about Chairman Sumeragi.
關於條皇評議會議長的事
My father?
我父親
The man who killed him
殺了他的人…
was me.
是我
Kagero...
陽炎
Kagero, now is not the time for one of your jokes.
陽炎 現在別開這種玩笑
No, I think he is serious about this.
不 看起來不像玩笑
Kagero...
陽炎…
SCARLET NEXUS
《緋紅結繫》
♫Felling of tiredness is losing yourself♫
倦怠感 losing yourself
♫How do you still create a relationship each other♫
尚未找到建立關係的方法嗎
♫It's my awkward friend's fault♫
有個麻煩的朋友
♫Until death, wanting someone somewhere to embrace me♫
至死都在尋求某人的擁抱
♫While the devil is not here and between the chaos♫
在得以喘息的混沌虛無之間
♫Aiming between win and lose♫
以輸贏之間為目標
♫Not to be running out of patience for now, I'm trying to be careful♫
注意別讓信任走向盡頭 務必小心
♫You'll see I'm always on your side♫
You'll see I'm always on your side
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地聯繫著
♫You're frigid and your roller coaster inside the brain♫
你腦中那冷感的軌道
♫The grungy days and the unprecedented catastrophy♫
搖滾的日子未曾有過的浩劫
♫Where is the glory buried?♫
光榮早已埋葬在某處
♫The lonely monster in a moment♫
這一瞬間寂寞孤獨的野獸
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
與機關槍射出的子彈並列
♫To pierce with the theory♫
射穿所有世間道理
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地聯繫著
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
與機關槍射出的子彈並列
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天也仍在一起 清晰地聯繫著
♫You're frigid and the theory in the brain♫
你那腦中冷感的正義
"KAGERO'S CONFESSION" Kagero, what are you talking about?
(陽炎的告解) 陽炎 你突然說什麼啊
I told you, I was a spy from Togetsu.
我之前曾說過 我是渡月的間諜
Chairman Sumeragi didn't trust Togetsu.
皇議長並不信任渡月
He didn't know all the secrets about the Red Strings.
雖尚未掌握紅色繫線的事
But he seemed to have noticed Togetsu's plan.
但似乎察覺渡月的企圖
So Togetsu saw the Chairman as a threat.
所以渡月認為 議長的存在是個麻煩
Indeed.
沒錯
That was why I was sent to Suoh
因此 把我送到蘇芳
to join the OSF
讓我加入怪伐軍
so I could assassinate him.
尋找暗殺的機會
I thought you wanted to stop Togetsu's plan.
你不是想阻止渡月的企圖嗎
Yes. That is the reason.
是啊 所以才這麼做啊
I can't let the people from Togetsu to question my loyalty.
我不能讓渡月那群人認為我有異心
I had to follow their orders.
必須聽命行事
I don't personally hate the Chairman.
實際上我並不恨議長
But I had to do it for my own sake.
但這麼做是為了自己
To simply put, I was
簡單來說 就是…
saving my own skin.
明哲保身吧
Wait, what are you talking about?
等等 你到底在說什…
Kasane, you were there too.
重 當時妳也在場吧
I think the Chairman told you something.
我想議長應該跟妳說
"He was in the OSF."
"是…怪伐軍…"
"He's a spy from Togetsu."
"那是… 渡月的間諜"
I am the spy he spoke of.
他說的間諜就是我
And then the Chairman told
之後 議長又說
to leave him behind and get to shelter.
"別在意我 快去避難" 對吧
OSF...
怪伐軍的…
Togetsu...
那是… 渡… 的…
Leave me behind. Get to shelter.
別管我… 去避難…
Yes, he said that.
對 他確實這麼說了
Yuito arrived soon after.
接著 結人就趕過來了
-That means... -So Kagero, it was your doing.
-那麼… -意思是 真的是陽炎你…
All right. You got it now.
好了 你懂了吧
Is it true?
真的嗎
Did you really do it?
真的是你…
Weren't you listening to me at all?
我剛才就是這麼說的啊
But why?
為什麼
Why do you bring it up now?
為什麼現在要說這件事
I'm apologizing to you.
我現在跟你道歉
Does the reason really matter now?
至於是什麼原因 不重要吧
Although I know for certain you wouldn't forgive me.
我知道 你不會原諒我
What will you do now?
所以你打算怎麼做
If you want me to be gone for good, I'll respect your decision.
如果你希望我消失的話 我也會尊重你的想法
Is this how you see it?
這就是你的做法嗎
Yes.
是啊
This is exactly who I am.
我就是這種人
Then, I shall put an end to this my way.
那我就用我的做法 讓一切做個了結
Yuito.
結人
Come on, you can't be serious about this.
來這招啊 你該不會是認真的吧
Young Master.
小少爺
Do you really want a fight?
你真的要打嗎
Fight me.
跟我打一場吧
I'm dead serious!
我是… 認真的
Yuito, Kagero, stop it!
住手 結人 陽炎
Leave them be.
別打擾他們
Why?
為什麼
They will never move on unless they fight.
不讓他們打一場 就無法前進
This is boring. Wake me up when the fight is over.
無聊 他們打完了再叫我
A spoiled young master like you would actually dare to fight me?
像你這種養尊處優的小少爺 好意思跟我較真
You are no match for me!
我不信你辦得到
Damn it.
可惡
I can't stay focused.
無法集中精神
Yuito, your power...
結人 你的力量…
This kid is really trying to take my life!
這傢伙 是真的想殺我…
Are you kidding me?
開什麼玩笑
I can't die just yet.
我還不能死
Wait, Yuito! You can't kill me just yet.
等等 結人 先別殺我
Damn it!
可惡
Wait, Yuito!
等等 結人
If I die now...
我死了的話…
two thousand years' worth of effort
為了那孩子…
will go down the drain if I die now!
我這兩千年的努力 都將白費了
You finally told me the truth, Kagero.
你終於說實話了 陽炎
What?
什…什麼
Did you...
你該不會…
You wouldn't tell me the truth unless I get serious.
不這麼做 你就不會說實話
Unbelievable.
你真的是…
You haven't told me the whole story.
你還有沒坦白的事吧
-This way! -Please come here immediately.
-請到這裡 -來到我身邊
Regroup in Seiran!
聚集到青藍
Together, we will punish
讓我們一同討伐
New Himuka's system!
新日向的體制
You're...
你是…
Are you a soldier of OSF?
怪伐軍的隊員嗎
Perfect timing.
你來得正好
-Thank you. -Sorry.
-謝謝你 -不好意思
It's too early to thank me,
要道謝還太早了
Chairman Jo Sumeragi.
條皇評議會議長大人
Are you with the rebels?
你也是反叛軍嗎
No.
答錯了
But Seiran's attack on Suoh created the perfect opening for me.
多虧青藍攻擊蘇芳 為我製造了大好機會
I should thank Karen and his rebels for this.
我很感謝卡連和反叛軍
I see. You work for Togetsu.
是嗎 你是渡月的
Correct.
這次答對了
If you wanted me dead, why would you save me?
既然要殺我 為何還救我
I have my own agenda.
我有我的目的
I'll tell Togetsu you've been eliminated.
我會跟渡月報告已殺了你
Please go into hiding for the time being.
所以請你暫時躲起來
I'll provide you with shelter.
我會提供安全的地方給你
Are you betraying Togetsu? But why?
你要背叛渡月嗎 為什麼
As I said, I have my own agenda.
我說過了 我有我的目的
Well?
你決定如何
I refuse the offer.
我拒絕
New Himuka is in chaos.
新日向正陷入混亂
As a Sumeragi, I cannot forsake my people.
身為皇家人 絕不能拋下國民
Even if I spare you,
就算我不殺了你
Togetsu will still come after you.
渡月也不會放過你
You still have two amazing sons.
皇家還有兩位了不起的兒子吧
The rising star of OSF,
眾所期待的怪伐軍新星
Yuito Sumeragi
結人皇
and Chief Kaito Sumeragi.
和本部長 界人皇
Your job will be a lot easier if you let them handle some of the work.
暫時交給他們 你也能輕鬆不少
You must already know what my family has done.
你應該知道 皇家究竟做了什麼
Yuito is still unaware of the secrets our family and this country is hiding.
結人還不知道 這個國家 和皇家的事
Kaito misinterpreted Yakumo Sumeragi's intention.
界人則是誤解了八雲皇的意志
Yakumo would never want a war to break out.
戰亂 絕不是八雲的期望
The actions of the Sumeragi family and New Himuka cannot be forgiven
皇家 新日向 對國民的所作所為
even for the sake of maintaining peace and harmony.
就算是為了守護和平的生活 也絕不能被原諒
This is why I cannot go into hiding or let myself get killed.
所以 我不能躲起來 更不能死
I don't just want to save the country, I want to correct all the sins it's committed.
不只是為了拯救國家危機 和矯正過去的錯誤
I want my sons to inherit my legacy.
更是為了將我的思念 傳達給兒子們
You turned out to be more righteous than I had anticipated.
比我想的還要正派嘛
Just like the other ancestors.
跟他祖先一樣
It's harder to kill you now that you've mentioned that.
你都說成這樣 我反而更難殺你了
But I need you to come with me.
不過 還是請你跟我走一趟
Back down!
退下
Damn it.
可惡
Chairman Sumeragi!
皇議長
Chairman Sumeragi! Hang in there.
皇議長 振作點
Are you going to correct the wrongs of this country?
你打算 矯正國家過去的錯誤嗎
Father...
爸爸…
I didn't killed him myself.
雖然不是我直接下手的
But he died right after the conversation was over.
但我話才說完 議長就…
I might as well have done so.
跟我殺了沒兩樣
That's why you wanted to return to Togetsu and finish the job.
所以 你才想回渡月前做個了斷
You were merely trying to provoke us just now.
你剛才是故意挑釁的吧
I don't mind if I died by Yuito's blade.
就算死在結人手上我也無怨言
But to spill the truth in the end...
但是 最後卻吐露出真心話…
I don't want to die.
我不想死
Before I put an end to Togetsu's plan,
阻止渡月的陰謀之前
I can't die.
我還不能死
Tsugumi, thank you.
鶇 謝謝妳
You mentioned something about a kid.
你剛才說 "為了那孩子"
You mentioned it when we were in Togetsu.
你在渡月時也曾說
Your family is still on the Moon.
月球上有你的家人
Is that kid...
"那孩子"該不會就是…
Yes, it's my daughter.
是啊 是我女兒
My wife and daughter are on the Moon.
月球上 有我的妻子和女兒
If history is rewritten,
如果一切都重來
my daughter will cease to exist.
我女兒的存在就會消失
I can't allow that to happen.
我絕不允許這種事情發生
I can't let Togetsu get their hands on the Red Strings.
絕不能讓渡月使用紅色繫線
It's been 2000 years.
雖然已經過了2000年
They probably passed away.
她們可能早就去世了
You might think I am a fool.
你們一定覺得我在說傻話
But for me,
可是 對我來說
my family and daughter still exist.
我的家人 那孩子是存在的事實
My father used his power as the chairman to stop the country's wrongdoing.
我父親 以政府首長的身分 阻止這個國家的過錯
My father may have indirectly caused Nagi and Naomi's death.
那岐和直見的遭遇 或許就是我父親造成的
But for me, he is still my father.
但對我來說 他還是我唯一的父親
This is why I can understand why you want to your family to exist.
也因此 我能理解 你不希望消除家人存在的心情
When I lost my memories in Arahabaki,
在荒吐神失去過去回憶時
I was terrified.
我很害怕
I lost myself.
失去自我的感覺
I don't want anyone else to feel the same way.
我不希望別人也體驗到這種感受
Everyone needs their past and memories.
人 絕不能失去過去
We must stop Togetsu's plan.
阻止渡月吧
I still can't forgive Kagero,
我雖然還無法原諒陽炎
but I think I'll have no problem fighting Togetsu by your side.
不過 我想我能跟你一同 與渡月戰鬥
You are much more mature than I expected.
你啊… 想法比我還成熟
No. It was me who acted like a child.
不 應該是我太像小孩子了
In the end, you realized the truth.
最後 還是讓你有所覺悟
How embarrassing.
我真丟臉
Yuito, let me assist you on your way to stop Togetsu.
結人 務必讓我協助你 阻止渡月的企圖
Yes.
好
I think it stopped.
好像停了
That vibration was no normal earthquake.
剛才的晃動 似乎不是普通的地震
Yes. It was quite similar to the earthquake we encountered on the Kunad Highway.
對 像不像在岐高速公路上 遇到的地震
Is everyone all right?
各位 沒事吧
There has been some anomaly with the Kunad Gate.
岐之門突然出現異常的數值
The whole New Himuka could feel the earthquake.
新日向因此受到強烈的晃動
There have been no casualties so far.
雖然沒出現什麼傷亡
We are safe too.
我們也沒事
There hasn't been an avalanche at the mountain either.
寒冽山沒引起山崩
Does it mean the Kunad Gate has grown larger?
意思是岐之門擴大了嗎
The gate is being maintained by my power.
是我的超腦力 維持了岐之門
The gate will disappear after I die.
我死了 岐之門也會消失
That is the only way for the gate to be eliminated.
這便是讓岐之門消失的唯一辦法
Was it because of my power?
因我的力量而引起的嗎…
Togetsu must have some researches regarding the Kunad Gate.
渡月應該對岐之門有所研究吧
Yes. While we are stopping BABE,
有 停止貝比運作的同時
we could dig up some useful information.
順便調閱一些有用的情報吧
We could even find a better plan there.
搞不好能找到更好的方法
Yuito.
結人
How is your power lately?
最近你的腦力情況如何
Do you feel discomfort when you use your power?
使用超腦力時 還有不舒服的感覺嗎
No.
不 沒有
After I was saved by all of you in Arahabaki,
自從在荒吐神被大家救了之後
the headache stopped.
就不再頭痛了 沒什麼問題
Why is that?
為什麼會這樣
I'm glad to hear that.
那就好
When I was fighting you,
因為我跟你戰鬥時
how do I put it...
該怎麼說呢…
I could sense the abnormal power surge from you.
感覺你的身體湧出異常的超腦力
It might be because you were agitated at that moment.
但也可能是 當時你的情緒比較激動吧…
Power can be affected by emotions.
超腦力 確實會受到情緒影響
But if that wasn't the cause...
不過 如果不是這個原因…
It could be a sign of the power disappearing.
也有一種說法是 "腦力消失的徵兆"
Disappearing power will have a surge of strength.
即將消失的腦力 似乎會暫時異常提升
Is my power fading away?
我的腦力會消失嗎
As the brain grows older,
隨著腦本身的年紀增長
there could be signs of it.
而觀察到的少數現象
But Yuito's condition is...
跟結人現在的情況…
Yuito's brain has been under all sorts of damages.
可是 至今結人的腦 受到許多重大的衝擊
Not to mention I was born a Bell Pepper.
而且 我好像原本是甜椒…
What do you mean?
什麼意思
You were a Bell Pepper?
你是甜椒
You gained your power after the experiment.
小時候因實驗而成為了超腦力者
Even you were once a Bell Pepper.
沒想到連你都是甜椒
Are you sure about this?
會不會是弄錯了
I'm not entirely certain,
雖然我不確定
but after listening to Luka's stories about him and his brother,
但聽了魯卡和卡連的過去後
I feel like I was once powerless too.
覺得自己好像也是…
That could be true.
我覺得 很有可能
How long will my power last?
我的超腦力 還能維持多久
Will I start seeing anomalies in the next few days?
會不會就在這兩天 出現異狀…
I doubt it would happen so quickly.
應該不會這麼快
There haven't been a lot of recorded cases. I can't be too sure either.
但案例不多 我也不敢肯定
So, we don't know for sure what might happen.
還不確定就會這樣吧
Let's not draw any conclusion right away.
先別這麼快下定論
Indeed.
也是
Our priority is to reach Togetsu.
現在 先盡快去渡月吧
Understood.
我知道了
I'll take point and welcome you there.
那我打頭陣 然後迎接你們
Yes. We'll count on you.
好 拜託了
-It's open. -Let's go.
-開了 -走吧
Hurry up.
動作快
The enemies know we've infiltrated the place.
我們潛入進來的事 已經被發現了
Go straight toward BABE.
一口氣直衝到貝比裡
They are here.
來了
They are well-prepared.
準備得真周到
Breakthrough their ranks.
突破重圍
Yuito! Kasane!
結人 重
The enemies really want their brains.
你們似乎真的很想要他們的腦
I'll use my teleportation.
我要使用瞬間移動
Gather around now.
各位 快聚集過來
-Luka... -Are you going to teleport to BABE?
-魯卡 -你打算瞬間移動到貝比裡嗎
Isn't that a little too risky?
會不會有危險
I've confirmed the layout
這棟建築物的構造
of this building when we last came.
上次來時 我已經確認過了
As long as we are near BABE, they won't risk attacking us.
只要到貝比附近 對方就不會隨便出手
Yuito, hurry up!
結人 快
I'll be right there.
我馬上過去
Luka, begin now.
魯卡 開始吧
Here I go.
要開始囉
Yuito!
結人
I think we've reached BABE safely.
好像平安抵達貝比裡了
It went well.
順利…成功了…
How are you feeling?
沒事吧
You need some rest.
要不要休息一下
No. Thank you for your concern.
不用 謝謝妳為我著想
We should get going.
但我們還是快點吧
Haruka, Wataru.
遙 渡
Psynet connection has been shut down in here.
腦內對話果然斷了
Indeed.
是啊
This is stronger than the earthquake just now.
比剛才的地震還要晃
Is this caused by the Kunad Gate as well?
這也是岐之門造成的嗎
Hurry.
動作快
Hold on.
請等一下
Please hear me out.
請聽我說
This voice...
這個聲音…
Could it be...
難道…
Please hear me out.
請聽我說
-Mother! -Mom!
-媽媽
♫I'm troubled by my own yearning♫
被追求的憧憬所困
♫Unveil the blocked sun ray♫
揭開被阻擋的搖曳陽炎
♫There's a stranger in me♫
There's a stranger in me
♫That I've never seen♫
從未見過
♫I can not soar in the sky without fear♫
自己能不再恐懼翱翔高空
♫I'm spreading my wings♫
I'm spreading my wings
♫Dancing gracefully like a bird♫
華麗舞步的鳥兒
♫And gazing towards the scarlet sky♫
仰望染紅的天空
♫I chased after the gust♫
追過了強風
♫The scenery spreads into the ever-changing world♫
景色蔓延在千變萬化的世界裡
♫Inside the intertwined brilliance♫
在交錯的光芒中
♫I'm still searching for tomorrow's direction♫
持續尋找明天的行徑方向
♫Tomorrow's in your hands♫
Tomorrow's in your hands
♫Don't tell me now you're afraid♫
Don't tell me now you're afraid
♫There's no time to waste♫
There's no time to waste
♫Go forward♫
前進
♫Have no fear for anything♫
不再畏懼何物
♫Now, let's go♫
走吧
♫Into a brand new day♫
Into a brand new day
REUNION
(重逢)